{"tossups": [{"question": "The tyrant Peisistratos [[pye-see-STRAH-tohs]] recalled this military figure's father, Cimon [[KYE-mohn]] Coalemos, from exile after Cimon dedicated his chariot victory in the Olympics to that politician. Political rivals used this man's failed expedition to Paros to have him jailed where he died of gangrenous wounds suffered at the hands of the Persians. This <em>strategos</em> [[strah-TEH-gohs]] defeated Datis and Artaphernes at a battle which ended Darius the Great's invasion of Greece. For the point, name this Athenian general, the victor at the Battle of Marathon.", "answer": "<b><u>Miltiades</u></b> the Younger", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "In this period, the refusal to arrest Major Vojislav Tankosi\u0107 [[YOY-ih-slahf tahn-KOH-sitch]] and dissolve the <em>Narodna Odbrana</em> led to an increase in world tension. Edward Grey's failure during this period to prevent the outbreak of war led to his quote \"The lamps are going out all over Europe. We shall not see them lit again in our time.\" Minister of War Erich von Falkenhayn and Secretary Arthur Zimmerman backed a \"Blank Cheque\" by Kaiser Wilhelm issued during this period, committing the German Empire to war. An ultimatum from Austria-Hungary to Serbia following the death of Archduke Franz Ferdinand occurred during, for the point, which \"Crisis\" prior to the outbreak of World War One?", "answer": "<b><u>July</u></b> Crisis (prompt on descriptive answers like \"the fallout from the  assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand\"; prompt on \"lead-up to (or outbreak of) World War One\" until mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Despite praising it, Robert Remini claimed that a speech about this program was riddled with \u201cstatistical errors\u201d and \u201cwrongheadedness about Southern interests.\u201d A desire to bolster commerce and transportation led to this plan\u2019s proposal of canals that were part of a set of \u201cinternal improvements.\u201d The passing of the Tariff of 1816 and the creation of the Second Bank of the United States are considered major wins for this policy program. For the point, name this Whig economic plan introduced by Henry Clay.", "answer": "<b><u>American System</u></b> (prompt on \"American School\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Thomson's Lamp is a supertask that tests a postulate created by a philosopher with this name, one of whose theories was tested by Archimedes through his \"method of exhaustion.\" Another man with this name from Cyprus taught from the \"Painted Porch\" on the north side of the Athenian <em>Agora</em>. A follower of the Eleatic School with this name defended his mentor, Parmenides, in a set of namesake paradoxes that claimed that motion is an illusion. For the point, give this name of two Greek philosophers, including one from Citium [[KIT-ee-um]] who founded Stoicism.", "answer": "<b><u>Zeno</u></b> (accept <b><u>Zeno</u></b> of Citium; accept <b><u>Zeno</u></b> of Elea)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this conspiracy, the firebrand judge Roland Freisler used the \"People's Court\" for public show trials. Despite coming into contact with known plotter Johannes Popitz, Heinrich Himmler did nothing to stop this conspiracy, as he believed the ongoing war to be unwinnable. This plot, which occurred in East Prussia, began when a bomb in a briefcase was placed in a meeting room in an attempt to kill the F\u00fchrer. Claus von Stauffenberg led, for the point, which 1944 attempt to kill Hitler in the Wolf's Lair, which led to the death of Erwin Rommel?", "answer": "Operation <b><u>Valkyrie</u></b> (or Unternehmen <b><u>Walk\u00fcre</u></b>; accept <b><u>July Plot</u></b>; or <b><u>20 July</u></b> <b><u>1944</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Entries like \u201cCengunm\u00e9\u201d and \u201cSokaku-Reibo\u201d were included in these objects. Ann Druyan\u2019s brainwaves were included in these things, which also feature Jon Lomberg\u2019s \u201cDiagram of vertebrate evolution.\u201d The inclusion of Chuck Berry\u2019s \u201cJohnny B. Goode\u201d was a source of controversy regarding these objects, which bear similarity to the Pioneer plaques. Resembling time capsules, the creation of these items was supported by Carl Sagan. For the point, name these objects depicting human life that were sent as part of a namesake 1977 space mission.", "answer": "<b><u>Voyager</u></b> Golden <b><u>Record</u></b>s (prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {"question": "Corporate raider Carl Icahn [[\"ICON\"]] acquired this company in a leveraged buyout in 1988. This company sponsored the <em>Moonliner</em> at Disneyland, and it was originally founded to fly Ford Trimotors between New York and Los Angeles. The explosion of this company's Flight 800 resulted in a four year investigation on suspicion of terrorism. A terminal designed by Eero Saarinen for this company at JFK Airport was converted into a hotel in 2019. For the point, name this formerly Howard Hughes-owned airline that was acquired by American in 2001.", "answer": "<b><u>Trans World</u></b> Airlines (or <b><u>TWA</u></b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "During this war, Operation Hiroshima was an offensive by mercenaries led by Taffy Williams to capture the city of Onitsha. While jailed for being a dissident during this war, Wole Soyinka wrote several protest poems on toilet paper. Political dominance by the Muslim Hausa-Fulani people led to this conflict, which began when officer Odumegwu Ojukwu [[oh-duh-MEHG-woo oh-JOO-kwoo]] revolted against a Lagos-based government. A namesake Igbo breakaway region agitated for independence in, for the point, which 1960s war in southeastern Nigeria?", "answer": "<b><u>Biafra</u></b> War (accept Nigerian-<b><u>Biafra</u></b>n War; accept <b><u>Nigerian Civil</u></b> War before \"Nigeria\" is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Prior to this battle, Conservative leader Juan Almonte issued a proclamation that the invading side was benevolent. The winning side of this battle was pursued by Charles de Lorencez, who had defeated them in the earlier Battle of Acultzingo. This battle was fought between the hills containing Fort Loreto and Fort Guadalupe. In this battle, Ignacio Zaragoza defeated a better-equipped force that had marched from Veracruz. For the point, name this morale-boosting battle from the French invasion of Mexico, celebrated in the holiday Cinco de Mayo.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Puebla</u></b> (or Batalla de <b><u>Puebla</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A company founded by this man employed steamboat captain Joseph LaBarge and used a ship called the <em>Macedonian</em> as part of this man's opium ventures. The Robert Stuart House served as a key location for this organization on Mackinac [[MAK-in-naw]] Island. An estate that constituted nearly one percent of the U.S. GDP was left by this man, who is considered America\u2019s earliest multimillionaire. A port city in Oregon is named after this man, who made his fortune trading the product of trappers. For the point, name this German-born founder of the American Fur Company.", "answer": "John Jacob <b><u>Astor</u></b> (or Johann Jakob <b><u>Astor</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Michael Hillegas [[HILL-eh-gass]] was the first person to hold this position under the Articles of Confederation. Harry Truman appointed Georgia Neese Clark as the first woman to this position, and she was succeeded by Ivy Baker Priest. Jovita Carranza [[hoh-VEE-tah kah-RAHN-zah]] resigned from this position in 2020 to lead the Small Business Administration. It's not the Secretary of the Treasury, but this person's signature appears on U.S. banknotes. For the point, name this government position responsible for overseeing the Bureau of Engraving & Printing and the U.S. Mint.", "answer": "<b><u>Treasurer</u></b> of the United States (or U.S. <b><u>Treasurer</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"treasury secretary\" or \"Secretary of the Treasury\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A fizzled coup against this man's government was supported by British general Alfred Knox. The Kornilov Affair may have attempted to overthrow this man, who became the head of government following the July Days that forced the resignation of Georgy Lvov. A July 1917 operation named for this man was the last Russian offensive in World War One, commanded by Aleksei Brusilov. The Bolsheviks overthrew, for the point, which head of the Russian Provisional Government?", "answer": "Alexander <b><u>Kerensky</u></b> (or Alexander Fyodorovich <b><u>Kerensky</u></b>; accept <b><u>Kerensky</u> </b>Offensive)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "With technical support from Hezbollah, this faction launched its propaganda wing through the television channel Almasirah. This movement, which is dominated by the theology of the Zaidi [[ZAY-dee]] sect of Shia Islam, assassinated former president and one-time ally Ali Abdullah Saleh on claims of treason. This movement established the Supreme Political Council after seizing the Presidential Palace and forcing Abdrabbuh Mansur Hadi to flee to neighboring Saudi Arabia. For the point, name this Islamist political movement led by a namesake Yemeni tribe that conquered Sana'a in 2014.", "answer": "<b><u>Houthi</u></b>s (or <b><u>Houthi</u></b> Movement; accept <b><u>Ansar Allah</u></b>; prompt on \"Supreme Political Council\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Saint Gobnait [[GOB-nat]] supposedly hurled skeps used in this industry to ward off cattle thieves stealing from her Cork convent. In the treatise \"Golden Rules of Business Success,\" political figure Fan Li suggested using wooden boxes in this discipline to increase the quality of a certain foodstuff. In the early 20th century, the Isle of Wight experienced the first well-recorded instance of \"Colony Collapse Disorder,\" wiping out much of this industry. Honey is a byproduct of, for the point, which form of animal husbandry?", "answer": "<b><u>Beekeep</u></b>ing (accept word forms and descriptive answers involving <b><u>Bee</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Api</u></b>culture; accept <b><u>Apiary</u></b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {"question": "The spacesuit of this man was repossessed over claims he never returned it after bringing it to a show-and-tell. A 2021 video analysis of a certain vessel's splashdown suggested that an electrical discharge caused a hatch to burst rather than being manually released by this man. This man said, \u201cHow are we gonna get to the moon if we can\u2019t talk between two or three buildings?\u201d before dying in a fire during a pre-launch test. A pilot for Project Mercury and Project Gemini, for the point, which astronaut died while commanding the never-launched Apollo 1?", "answer": "Virgil \"Gus\" <b><u>Grissom</u></b> (or Virgil Ivan <b><u>Grissom</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In October 2021, a museum dedicated to this event was dedicated by President Emmanuel Macron. This event was sparked after a housekeeper named \u201cMadame Bastian\u201d discovered a torn-up note in the trash addressed to Max von Schwartzkoppen. The central figure of this event was pardoned by President \u00c9mile Loubet [[loo-BEH]] after spending over four years imprisoned on Devil's Island. Condemned by \u00c9mile Zola in the article <em>J\u2019accuse...!</em>, for the point, what polarizing affair involved a French artillery officer of Jewish descent who was convicted of treason?", "answer": "<b><u>Dreyfus</u></b> Affair (or L'affaire <b><u>Dreyfus</u></b>; accept descriptive answers involving the affair surrounding Alfred <b><u>Dreyfus</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A monk wrote the <em>Ormulum</em> in this language, interpreting how the homily should be given during Mass. The development of William Caxton's printing press led to the transition of this language to its \"Early Modern\" counterpart due to standardization. This language began to undergo the \"Great Vowel Shift\" in the 14th and 15th centuries, changing how long vowels were pronounced. <em>The Canterbury Tales</em> were written in, for the point, what language, influenced by both Norse and Norman French?", "answer": "<b><u>Middle English</u></b> (prompt on \"English\"; do not prompt on or accept \"Old English\")", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Linguistics"}, {"question": "The artist of this work chose to forgo a list of names the subject had in their possession and replaced it with a letter that said, \u201cGiven that I am unhappy, I have a right to your help.\u201d The person who committed the act depicted in this work had her own portrait painted by a National Guard officer hours before her execution. Although not specifically shown in this painting, the subject of this work suffered from dermatitis herpetiformis which required medicinal soaks. For the point, what 1793 painting by Jacques-Louis David depicts a French revolutionary leader after his murder by Charlotte Corday?", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Death of Marat</u></b></em> (or <em>La</em> <em><b><u>Mort de Marat</u></b></em>; or <em><b><u>Marat Assassin\u00e9</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Ethnic tensions between this leader's group and an Asian federation's <em>Bumiputeras</em> led to his country's expulsion from that union in the midst of a confrontation with Sukarno's Indonesia. This leader founded the People's Action Party, and despite controversies such as his lawsuits against political opponents, was credited with enabling his country, whose symbols include the merlion and red dot, to \"enter the first world\" in his lifetime. For the point, name this founder and first Prime Minister of Singapore.", "answer": "<b><u>Lee</u></b> Kuan Yew (or Harry <b><u>Lee</u></b> Kuan Yew; accept Harry <b><u>Lee</u></b>; accept <b><u>LKY</u></b>; prompt on \"Yew\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Guy S. Hopkins wrote a hoax letter suggesting this person was a part of a plan to overthrow the government. Opponents of this person ridiculed his alcoholism and referred to him as the \u201chero of many a well-fought bottle.\u201d Under the guidance of State Secretary William Marcy, this politician\u2019s administration published a document pushing for the U.S. annexation of Cuba, the Ostend Manifesto. This politician failed to become a second term president when he was defeated by his Minister to the United Kingdom, James Buchanan. For the point, what fourteenth president of the United States signed the Kansas-Nebraska Act?", "answer": "Franklin <b><u>Pierce</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A KGB-led disinformation campaign against this man's regime, named Operation TOUCAN, included the forging of a CIA letter approving a hit on a <em>New York Times</em> journalist by DINA. The \"Coalition of Parties for NO\" formed in the late 1980s in an attempt to peacefully replace this man. On his 60th birthday, the CIA launched Operation Condor to suppress left-wing movements in this man's nation and neighboring Argentina. The overthrow of Salvador Allende [[ah-YEHN-deh]] was carried out by, for the point, which Chilean dictator?", "answer": "Augusto <b><u>Pinochet</u></b> [[pee-noh-SHEH]] (accept Augusto Jos\u00e9 Ram\u00f3n <b><u>Pinochet</u> </b>Ugarte)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In a diary entry, this leader wrote of his adversary, \u201cHe has a soft-as-cotton outer layer but at the same time has sharp needles hiding inside,\u201d before saying, \u201cHe will be crushed inside my palm.\u201d With the help of the Blue Shirts Society and the CC Clique, this figure and his wife led the Neo-Confucian New Life Movement. Over 3,000 critics were executed as a result of martial law imposed by this leader in an event known as the White Terror. For the point, what \u201cGeneralissimo\u201d fled to Taiwan after losing to Mao Zedong in the Chinese Civil War?", "answer": "<b><u>Chiang</u></b> Kai-shek (accept <b><u>Chiang</u></b> Chung-cheng; accept <b><u>Chiang</u></b> Chieh-shih; accept <b><u>Cheung</u></b> Kai-shek; accept <b><u>Jiang</u></b> Jieshi; prompt on \"Kai-shek\"; prompt on \"Generalissimo\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This amendment was the subject of a decision written by Chief Justice Earl Warren in the case <em>Trop v. Dulles</em>. This amendment was referenced in the case <em>Weems v. United</em> <em>States</em>, in which the plaintiff was charged with falsifying an official document. In the case <em>United States v. Bajakajian</em>, the Supreme Court held that forfeiting over $350,000 violated a clause in this amendment. For the point, what amendment protects American citizens from \u201cexcessive fines\u201d and \u201ccruel and unusual punishments\u201d?", "answer": "<b><u>Eighth</u></b> Amendment", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A valley named after this group was excavated by a French painter named Paul Jamot [[zhah-MOH]], where he discovered that the sanctuary there also had a theatre. Pythagoras advised the people of Croton to build a shrine emulating this group in the middle of the city in order to promote learning. The main cult of these beings was based in Mount Helicon in Boeotia [[bee-OH-shah]]. Including Terpsichore [[terp-SIK-oh-ree]], Polyhymnia, and Clio, for the point, what nine \u201cinspirational\u201d goddesses in Greek mythology presided over the arts?", "answer": "<b><u>Muse</u></b>s", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "As a result of this treaty, the southern half of Sakhalin [[SAH-kah-leen]] Island was awarded to the victorious nation. This treaty gave one country the Liaodong [LEE-OW-DONG]] Peninsula in Manchuria, though that country's public expected more due to their overwhelming victories at battles like Tsushima Strait. For brokering this treaty, which the parties signed in Kittery, Maine, U.S. president Theodore Roosevelt received the Nobel Peace Prize. For the point, name this treaty signed in 1905 that ended the Russo-Japanese War.", "answer": "Treaty of <b><u>Portsmouth</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this war, Captain William Bainbridge, commander of the USS <em>Retaliation</em>, surrendered after he mistakingly believed the ships he encountered were his allies. One of those ships was eventually captured by Captain Thomas Truxton, commander of the USS <em>Constellation</em>, and was taken as a prize to Saint Kitts during this war. Diplomats Charles Cotesworth Pinckney, John Marshall, and Elbridge Gerry\u2019s failed attempt to meet Talleyrand led to this war. Ended by the Treaty of Mortefontaine, for the point, what undeclared naval war was fought between the United States and France?", "answer": "<b><u>Quasi</u></b>-War (or <em><b><u>Quasi</u></b>-guerre</em>; prompt on answers such as \"undeclared naval war with France\" before \"France\" is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this country, one leader gave the Apopa sermon following the deportation of Mario Londono. A U.N. Truth Commission held the Atlacatl [[aht-lah-KAH-tul]] Battalion responsible for a massacre that killed roughly 800 inhabitants in this county\u2019s village of El Mozote. The killing of Rutilio Grande in this country prompted liberation theologian, Archbishop \u00d3scar Romero, to refuse to attend state occasions. A violent 1979 to 1992 civil war was fought in, for the point, what country between Guatemala and Honduras?", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>El Salvador</u></b> (accept Rep\u00fablica de <b><u>El Salvador</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "An early example of these objects at the Metropolitan Museum of Art was created in Cremona by Andrea Amati and named for \"Charles IX [[the Ninth]].\" The Guarneri and Rugeri [[roo-GEH-ree]] families were known for manufacturing these objects in the late 17th and early 18th centuries. The \"Messiah\" is perhaps the most pristine of some 650 surviving examples of these instruments produced by a man who used dark varnish and intricate carvings. For the point, name these string instruments, whose notable creators include Antonio Stradivari.", "answer": "<b><u>Violin</u></b>s (or <b><u>Fiddle</u></b>; accept <b><u>Amati</u></b> before mentioned; prompt on \"Stradivarius\")", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "One of these objects, eventually used as a birdhouse, was developed by Lester Wire based on a British system. Ashville, Ohio claims to have had the oldest working example of these objects, which was in service for fifty years. William Potts developed an innovation of these devices by utilizing an \"amber\" light. The Acme Corporation built the first of these devices in Los Angeles, supplementing their most notable element with signs saying \"Stop\" and \"Go.\" In 1922, African-American inventor Garrett Morgan patented, for the point, what technology used to regulate car flow on roads?", "answer": "<b><u>Traffic Light</u></b>s (or <b><u>Traffic Signal</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Stoplight</u></b>s)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A propaganda tale during the First World War claimed Sergeant Harry Band suffered this form of punishment at the hands of German soldiers during the Battle of Ypres [[ee-PRAH]]. In Tokugawa Japan, <em>Haritsuke</em> was the practice of thrusting spears into criminals during this form of punishment. Six thousand participants of the Third Servile War were punished in this manner along the Appian Way. The most famous symbol of Christianity was used for, for the point, which form of capital punishment traditionally suffered by Jesus?", "answer": "<b><u>Crucifixion</u></b> (or <b><u>Crucify</u></b>ing; accept word forms; accept any mention of <b><u>Cross</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. The person who gave this speech said it was an honor to have known Jacob Ruppert, a former representative from New York. Existing film snippets only capture four sentences of this speech. The first number to have ever been retired in baseball history occurred the same day this speech was given, and this speech is often referred to as \u201cbaseball\u2019s Gettysburg Address.\u201d Given on the speaker\u2019s \u201cAppreciation Day,\u201d for the point, what speech was given by a New York Yankees first baseman on July 4, 1939?", "answer": "\"<b><u>Luckiest man</u></b> on the face of the earth\" speech (accept equivalents to Lou <b><u>Gehrig\u2019s farewell</u></b> address or Lou <b><u>Gehrig\u2019s retirement</u></b> speech)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<em>Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper</em> ran an 1858 expos\u00e9 on this good showing how the use of swill left over from distilleries in its production led to the deaths of over 8,000 children per year. Nancy Lincoln, the mother of Abraham Lincoln, died after consuming this product from an animal that had eaten a white snakeroot plant. For the point, name this nutrient-rich liquid product whose condensed form was developed in the U.S. by Gail Borden.", "answer": "Cow's <b><u>Milk</u></b> (accept Condensed <b><u>Milk</u></b>; accept Borden's <b><u>Milk</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this royal's reign, the Awbridge silver penny was introduced to combat inflation after a series of civil wars. This man rebuffed an attempt for the French King Philip II Augustus to to be both the guardian of his deceased son's family and the territory of Brittany. With support from his father-in-law Louis VII [[the seventh]], Henry the Young King attempted to seize the English throne from this man during the Great Revolt. The husband of Eleanor of Aquitaine and father of Richard the Lionhearted was, for the point, which Plantagenet who brought the Angevin Empire to the height of its territorial extent?", "answer": "<b><u>Henry II</u></b> (accept <b><u>Henry Curtmantle</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Antiochus [[ahn-TYE-oh-kus]] IV Epiphanes's puppet leader, the High Priest Jason, constructed one of these facilities in the Temple of Jerusalem, partially motivating the Maccabean Revolt. Plato claims the only two subjects an Athenian boy needed in his curricula were \"Music and\" access to this facility. In Delphi, wrestling schools known as the <em>Palaestra</em> were often constructed to adjoin these facilities. Training for Public Games occurred at, for the point, which Ancient Greek facility where men exercised in the nude?", "answer": "<b><u>Gym</u></b>nasium (accept <b><u>Gym</u></b>nasia; prompt on \"Palaestra\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This one-time colony experienced widespread race riots after Police Constable Beesoo was killed by a Creole gang, who went on ransack the village of Souillac [[soo-LAHK]]. Along with the Seychelles, the Chagossian Islanders were forcibly relocated to this nation in an effort by the UK to build a military base on Diego Garcia. Due to island tameness, a native bird of this island called the Dodo was hunted into extinction after its discovery by Europeans in the 16th and 17th century. For the point, name this country, the highest on the human development index in Africa, governed from Port Louis.", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Mauritius</u></b> (or R\u00e9publique de <b><u>Maurice</u></b>; or Repiblik <b><u>Moris</u></b>)  <b>Extra Questions </b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "Politician Vilhelm Knorin wrote a \"Short Course\" history of this nation that was used in schools until it was repudiated in the speech \"On the Cult of Personality and its Consequences.\" The fall of this nation led Francis Fukuyama to write <em>The End of History and</em> <em>the Last Man</em>, postulating an end to ideological evolution. Historiographical works were published in the <em>Political Journal</em> through the <em>samizdat</em>, a form of underground publishing in this nation. Native historian Roy Medvedev published a critique of, for the point, which nation, once led by Joseph Stalin?", "answer": "<b><u>Soviet Union</u></b> (or <b><u>USSR</u></b>; or <b><u>Union of Soviet Socialist Republics</u></b>; or <b><u>CCCP</u></b>; prompt on \"Russia\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}